americanmilitarynews.com 2019-06-05

# Privacy Policy

**Summary**

American Military News values your privacy and information more than most other news media companies.

AMN does not collect your information to simply sell it to other companies for cash. In fact, any information AMN directly collects from you stays in AMN’s hands and no one else gets to have it as their own.

When you see advertisements on AMN, those companies also collect information about you but it is anonymous information that they use to show you ads that you may find relevant on AMN and other places around the internet.

These companies most likely already have this other information before you visit AMN and you most likely see the ads you are seeing on AMN because they’ve tracked you around the web and know what you are interested in, and not interested in. By visiting AMN they now know you have visited the website and they then add that to your anonymous profile they have on you.

By visiting AMN, you agree to our Privacy Policy and we assume that you, as an adult, are aware of your own information on the internet, how the internet works, how visiting a website works and that you are an informed consumer.

We encourage you to visit the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use of every website you visit on the web.

If you are interested in the fine-print, you can read more below.

**How We Collect and Use Information**

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally identifiable information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains to you how we collect, use, and share information and Personal Data (as defined under applicable law) we obtain through your use of the Internet sites, applications and online services (“Services”) that are operated by, controlled by or affiliated with KellenProjects LLC, which operates AmericanMilitaryNews.com (collectively, “we,” “us” or “our”). This Privacy Policy only covers information collected through the Services and via direct communications between you and KellenProjects LLC (“KP”), and does not cover any information collected at any other website, application or otherwise by us (unless specifically stated), including when you call us, write to us, or communicate with us in any manner other than through the Services. By using the Services, you consent to such use of your information and Personal Data and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

We will only process your Personal Data in accordance with applicable data protection and privacy laws.

**_Information you provide us directly:_**

We ask for certain information such as a username, real name, birthdate, address, phone number and e-mail address during various circumstances, or if you correspond with us. We may also retain any messages you send through the Service, and may collect information you provide in User Content you post to the Service. We use this information to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service.

**_Information we may receive from third parties:_**

We may receive information about you from third parties. For example, if you access our websites or Service through a third-party connection or log-in, for example, through Facebook Connect, by “following,” “liking,” adding any American Military News applications, linking your account etc., that third party may pass certain information about your use of its service to KP. This information could include, but is not limited to, the user ID associated with your account (for example, your Facebook UID), an access token necessary to access that service, any information that you have permitted the third party to share with us, and any information you have made public in connection with that service. If you allow us access to your friends list, your friends’ user IDs, and your connection to those friends, may be used and stored to make your experience more social, and to allow you to invite your friends to use our Service as well as provide you with update. You should always review, and if necessary, adjust your privacy settings on third-party websites and services before linking or connecting them to the American Military News Service. You may also unlink your third party account from the Service by adjusting your settings on the third party service, if applicable.

**_Analytics information:_**

We may directly collect analytics data, or use third-party analytics tools and services, to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Service. These tools collect information sent by your browser or mobile device, including the pages you visit and other information that assists us in improving the Service.

**_Cookies information:_**

When you visit the Service, we may send one or more cookies — a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters — to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets you load the website faster and enhance your navigation through the site. A cookie may also convey information to us about how you use the Service (e.g., the pages you view, the links you click and other actions you take on the Service), and allow us or our business partners to track your usage of the Service over time. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

**_Log file information:_**

_ _ Log file information is automatically reported by your browser or mobile device each time you access the Service. When you use our Service, our servers automatically record certain log file information. These server logs may include anonymous information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with links on the Service, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

**_Clear gifs/web beacons information:_**

When you use the Service, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to anonymously track the online usage patterns of our Users. In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened and which links are clicked by recipients. The information allows for more accurate reporting and improvement of the Service.

**_Location data:_**

When you access the Service by or through a mobile device, we may access, collect, monitor and/or remotely store “location data,” which may include GPS coordinates (e.g. latitude and/or longitude) or similar information regarding the location of your mobile device. Location data may convey to us information about how you browse and use the Service. Some features of the Service, particularly location-based services, may not function properly if use or availability of location data is impaired or disabled.

**_Commercial and marketing communications:_**

We use the information we collect or receive, such as your email address, to communicate directly with you. We may send you emails containing newsletters, promotions, and special offers. If you do not want to receive such email messages, you will be given the option to opt out or change your preferences.

**_Use of certain service type information we collect about you:_**

We use or may use cookies, log file, device identifiers, location data and clear gifs information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) to provide and monitor the effectiveness of our Service; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns; (e) diagnose or fix technology problems; (f) help you efficiently access your information after you sign in; (g) to provide advertising to your browser or device, and (h) automatically update the American Military News application on your mobile devices.

**Sharing of Your Information**

We will not rent or sell your information into third parties outside KP without your consent, except as noted below:

  * Who we may share your information with: We may share your information with third-party business partners and Trusted Users for the purpose of providing the Service to you. Third party business partners will be given limited access to your information as is reasonably necessary to deliver the Service, and we will require that such third parties comply with this Privacy Policy, or operate under a similar privacy policy.

**_Instances where we are required to share your information:_**

KP will disclose your information where required to do so by law or subpoena or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) to enforce our Terms of Service or to protect the security, quality or integrity of our Service; and/or (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of KP, our Users, or others.

**_Sharing certain service type information we collect about you:_**

We may share certain service type information, including information obtained through tools such as cookies, log files, device identifiers, location data and clear gifs (such as anonymous usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.): (i) with our third-party business partners for the purposes described in the section above on “How We Collect and Use Information.” We may also aggregate or otherwise strip data of all personally identifying characteristics and may share that aggregated, anonymized data with third parties.

**_Ads on American Military News:_**

We may also share certain information such as your location, browser, and cookie data and other data relating to your use of our Service with our business partners to deliver advertisements (“ads”) that may be of interest to you. KP may allow third-party ad servers or ad networks to serve advertisements on the Service. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser or mobile device, the ads and ad links that appear on the Service, and will automatically receive your IP address when they do so. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, device identifiers, location data, and clear gifs, see above) to compile information about your browser’s or device’s visits and usage patterns on the Service and on other websites, and to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize the advertising content delivered to you.

For example, Google may use DART cookies in order to deliver ads to you through the Service. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to you based on your visit to the Service and previous websites that you may have visited. Other advertising networks also use similar cookies, clear gifs, or other mechanisms to deliver targeted advertising to you through the Service. You can delete these cookies by following the instructions here: http://www.wikihow.com/Clear-Your-Browser%27s-Cookies . You may opt out of use of Google’s DART cookie and cookies placed by Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) certified ad networks here: http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp . Opting out of these cookies will be effective not only on the Service, but on all websites with NAI certified advertising networks. However, these opt-outs will be ineffective on networks that are not NAI certified.

Please note that an advertiser may ask KP to show an ad to a certain audience of Users (e.g., based on demographics or other interests). In that situation, KP or our Partners determines the target audience and KP serves the advertising to that audience and only provides anonymous data to the advertiser. If you respond to such an ad, the advertiser or ad server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach.

To enhance your user experience or help us improve and measure our effectiveness, KP may embed code from third parties on the Service. Examples of such parties may include Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Google, YouTube, Howcast, VideoJug, AOL, and others. These third parties may collect information about you including IP address, cookies in ways KP does not control.

The KP Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of third-parties. Please consult the respective privacy policies of such third parties or contact such third parties for more information.

**How We Protect Your Information**

**_Keeping your information safe:_**

KP cares about the security of your information, and uses commercially reasonable safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of all information collected through the Service. KP cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to American Military News or guarantee that information on the Service may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed. Your privacy settings may also be affected by changes to the functionality of third party sites and services that you add to the American Military News Service, such as social networks. KP is not responsible for the functionality or security measures of any third party.

**_Compromise of information:_**

In the event that any information under our control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, KP will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and where appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other steps, in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations.

**Your Choices about Your Information**

We make every effort to promptly process all email unsubscribe requests. You can contact us directly at info@americanmilitarynews.com.

**_Opting out of collection of your information for Tracking / Advertising:_**

Please refer to your mobile device or browser’s technical information for instructions on how to delete and disable cookies, and other tracking/recording tools. Depending on your type of device, it may not be possible to delete or disable tracking mechanisms on your mobile device. Note that disabling cookies and/or other tracking tools prevents American Military News or its business partners from tracking your browser’s activities in relation to the Service, and for use in targeted advertising activities by third parties. However, doing so may disable many of the features available through the Service. If you have any questions about opting out of the collection of cookies and other tracking/recording tools, you can contact us directly at info@americanmilitarynews.com.

**Children’s Privacy**

KP does not knowingly collect or solicit any information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register as Users. The Service and its content are not directed at children under the age of 13. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at info@americanmilitarynews.com.

**Links to Other Websites and Services**

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites or services linked to or from the Service, including the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, our Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party websites or services. Your browsing and interaction on any third-party website or service, including those that have a link or advertisement on our website, are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies. In addition, you agree that we are not responsible and we do not control over any third-parties that you authorize to access your User Content. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources other than through the Service.
